Guide to the Darrell C. Crain, Jr., presidential inaugural collection, 1817-1989 MS2035
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Darrell C. Crain, Jr., presidential inaugural collection
1817-2009
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Crain, Darrell C.
MS2035
10 Linear Feet
The Darrell C. Crain, Jr. Presidential Inaugural Collection consist of newspaper articles, invitations, tickets programs, memorabilia, newspapers, invitations and souvenir booklets, pins and mini flags. The material dated from approximately 1957-1989 came from events such as inaugural ceremonies and balls that Dr. Crain attended while earlier memorabilia from 1817-1929 was material he purchased to complement the collection.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Darrell Crain to The George Washington University in 1989 and 1990.
Historical or Biographical Note
Dr. Darrell C. Crain, Jr. (1910-1995) graduated from The George Washington University Medical School in 1932. Crain's specialization was Rheumatology, which he practiced in the Washington area for fifty years. He was also a clinical professor at Georgetown University from 1971 to 1987.
Dr. Crain was not only in private practice, but also active in the field of Rheumatology. He was co-founder of the Arthritis Rehabilitation Center in Washington, DC and founder of the Rheumatology Clinic at Georgetown University Hospital. In addition to writing three books, Dr. Crain was chief of rheumatic diseases at Doctors Hospital, and a consultant to the surgeon general of the Army and the U.S. surgeon general.
Dr. Crain created his collection of inaugural coins in honor of his father, who designed the inaugural medals for President Wilson in 1917, President Harding in 1921 and President Coolidge in 1925. Crain's knowledge of inaugural medals earned him a position on the Official Inaugural Medal Committee for five U.S. presidents.
Dr. Crain was associated with inaugural history in other capacities as well as the Inaugural Medal Committee. He was president of the Medical Society of D.C., which provides emergency medical staff for inaugural events.
He was born in 1910 in Washington, DC. and passed away on July 22, 1995.
Collection Scope and Content
The Darrell C. Crain, Jr. Presidential Inaugural Collection consist of newspaper articles, invitations, tickets programs, memorabilia, newspapers, invitations and souvenir booklets, pins and mini flags. The material dated from approximately 1957-1989 came from events such as inaugural ceremonies and balls that Dr. Crain attended while earlier memorabilia from 1817-1929 was material he purchased to complement the collection.
Dr. Crain also donated a significant colletion of official presidential and vice-presidential medals. The presidential medals cover the Presidential Inaugurations of James Monroe, Andrew Jackson, Zachary Taylor, Franklin Pierce, Abraham Lincoln, Ulysses S. Grant, Chester A. Arthur, Benjamin Harrison, William McKinley, Theodore Roosevelt, Woodrow Wilson, Herbert Hoover, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Dwight D. Eisenhower, John F. Kennedy, Lyndon Johnson, Richard Nixon, Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter, Ronald Reagan and George Bush. The collection also contains invitations, tickets and programs collected by Dr. Crain during his participation in inaugural events such as the inaugural ceremonies and the inaugural balls. Dr. Crain had access to these events as a member of the Official Inaugural Medal Committee and the Inaugural Medical Committee. These medals are on display in the Special Collections reading room.
Collection Organization
Organized into ten series: Invitations, Tickets, Programs, Guide books, Commemorative material, Souvenirs, Clippins and articles, Miscellaneous, Oversized material, and Inagural medals.
Politics and government; Inaugurations; United States -- History; Washington (D.C.); Presidents; Crain, Darrell C.
- Invitations, 1881-1989; MS2035 Series 1; 1 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of invitations from 1881 to 1989, either sent to or collected by Dr. Crain. The invitations are to events such as the Reception of Governors and Special Distinguished Guests, the Inauguration Ceremony, the Inauguration Ball, and the Reception for the Vice President.
  - Invitations, Inaugural Reception & Promenade Concert, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremony, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Committee Reception, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ball, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invitations, Official Hostesses and Hospitality Committee Reception, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, Reception of Governors and Special Distinguished Guests, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremony, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, Honorary Invitation to Inaugural Ceremonies with Calendar of Major Events, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ball, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremonies with print of President, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Invitations, Vice President elect Reception, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremony, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ball, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremonies including prints of President and Vice President, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremony, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ball, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremonies including prints of President and Vice President, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Festivities at the Smithsonian Institute and other cultural centers in DC, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Opening Ceremonies, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremonies including prints of President and Vice President, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremony, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ball, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremony, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ball, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Tickets, 1929-1981; MS2035 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains tickets stubs and order forms from inaugural events from 1929-81, such as the Inagural Ceremony, the Inaugural Ball, the Youth Ball, the Reception of Governors and Special Distinguished Guests, inaugural festivities and opening ceremonies.
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ceremony, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Tickets, Correspondence, Information on Tickets, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ball, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Reception for Distinguished Ladies attending the Inaugural, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Festival, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ceremony, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ceremony, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Tickets, Reception for Governors and Special Distinguished Guests, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ceremony, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Tickets, Subscription Card for Inaugural Ball, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ball, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ceremony, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ball, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Youth Ball, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Tickets, Mailgram concerning invitations for events, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Tickets, Order Response Form for Events, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Registration Certificate, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Opening Ceremonies, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Tickets, Inaugural Ball, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Programs, 1889-1989; MS2035 Series 3; 1 Linear feet
  This series consists of programs from 1889 to 1989. These programs highlight events such as the Inaugural Ceremony, the Inaugural Ball, White House Worship Service, and the Reception for the Vice President.
  - Programs, Inaugural Ball, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Programs, Inaugural Parade Order, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ball, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremony, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies (2), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremony, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Programs, Pre Inaugural Service, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremony, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ball, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Programs, Inaugural Festival, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Programs, Pre Inaugural Services, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremony, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Programs, Inaugural Gala, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs, Inaugural Reception in Honor of Vice President elect and Mrs.Agnew, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Programs, Reception of the Governors and Special Distinguished Guests, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremony, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ball, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Programs, White House Worship Service, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Programs, Inaugural Reception in Honor of Vice President Elect George Bush and Mrs. Bush, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Programs, Inaugural Opening Ceremonies, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Programs, Inaugural Outdoor Band Concert, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Programs, Inaugural Ceremonies, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Guide books, 1917-1981; MS2035 Series 4; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series consists of guide books distributed to the public during inaugural events. The guidebooks illustrate highlights of the City of Washington and are dated 1917, 1953, 1973, and 1981.
  - Guide Books, Points of Historical Interest, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Guide Books, Complimentary Guide Book, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Guide Books, Inaugural Guide, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Guide Books, Official Guide Book, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Guide Books, "Where To Go, What To See", undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Commemorative material, 1977-1981; MS2035 Series 5; 1 Linear feet
  This series includes correspondence and catalogs from 1977-81. The catalogs illustrate inaugural commemorative material, primarily coins, which could be purchased.
  - Commemorative Material, Official Catalog, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Commemorative Material, Correspondence and Brochure, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Commemorative Material, Correspondence, Press Release, Price List, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Commemorative Material, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Commemorative Material, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Commemorative Material, Catalog, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Souvenirs, 1889-1989; MS2035 Series 6; 1 Linear feet
  This series contains souvenirs distributed or bought during the inaugural events such as printed copies of the 1957 and 1961 inaugural addresses, booklets, flags, presidential portrait prints, a menu and a button comprise this series. These objects date from 1889-1989. Of note is the collection of 1889 Inauguration souvenirs a booklet from the Inaugural Ball, a miniature "Harrison and Morton" flag, and a print of President Harrison and his wife.
  - Souvenirs, Souvenir Booklet for Inaugural Ball, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Souvenirs, Miniature Flag with "Harrison and Morton", 1889 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Souvenirs, Print of Benjamin Harrison and Wife, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Souvenirs, Engraving for Inaugural Ball and Reception, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Souvenirs, Souvenir Book of Inaugural Ceremonies, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Souvenirs, Inaugural Souvenir Book, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Souvenirs, Menu for Inaugural Ball Supper, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Souvenirs, Booklet, Women of Inaugural Committee, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Souvenirs, Floral Souvenir from Inaugural Ball, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Souvenirs, Bumper Sticker, "Support The President", Circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Souvenirs, Inaugural Address, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Souvenirs, Inaugural Address, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Souvenirs, Postcards from Sheraton Park Hotel, Circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Souvenirs, Calendar and Information on Inaugural Events, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Souvenirs, Diagram of Seating on President's Platform, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Souvenirs, Inaugural Activities, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Souvenirs, Parking Tag, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Souvenirs, Miniature Flag, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Souvenirs, Schedule of Events, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Souvenirs, Schedule of Events, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Souvenirs, Prints of Bush/Quayle, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Souvenirs, Button, Bush Inauguration, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Souvenirs, Engravings of Past Presidents, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Souvenirs, Prints of Washington and Lincoln, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Clippings and articles, 1953-1974; MS2035 Series 7; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series contains special editions of magazines and newspapers, published for the Inauguration. This documents date from 1953-74.
  - Clippings and Articles, 1953 January (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Clippings and Articles, "Life" Magazine, Inaugural Spectacle, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Clippings and Articles, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Clippings and Articles, "Time", The Healing Begins, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous, 1969-1987; MS2035 Series 8; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series contains papers and artifacts, which were not appropriate to include in the previous series, but concerned the inaugurations and Dr. Crain's participation in them. Correspondence from the General Inaugural Committee and the Inaugural Medical Committee and a thank you form letter from President Nixon comprise this series. Unrelated political material, collected by Dr. Crain, such as a Republican Heritage Calendar from 1969 and an invitation for the 1987 Inauguration of DC Mayor Marion Barry complete the series.
  - Miscellaneous, Correspondence, Members of the General Inaugural Committee, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, Clipping with tally of electoral votes, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, Thank You Card from President Nixon for those who assisted with the Inauguration, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous, Republican Heritage Calendar, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous, Correspondence, Inaugural Medical Committee, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous, Correspondence, Inaugural Medical Committee, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, Invitation to Inauguration of Mayor of DC, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Oversized material, 1817-1993; MS2035 Series 9; 1 Linear feet
  This series consists of oversized documents, ranging from an invitation to the Inaugural Ceremony to newspaper articles on inaugural speeches. The series is an artificial series of material too big to fit in with its orignal series and its order reflects those original series.
  - Invitations, Inaugural Ceremony, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Commemorative Material, Inaugural Cover Collection, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Souvenirs, Prints, "Inaugural Views", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1833-1837 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1849-1863 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1868-1869 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1881-1893 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Clippings & Articles, "Life" Magazine, Johnson, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Clippings & Articles, "Convention & Election Almanac", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper Special Edition, "Six Great Moments In the White House", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Clippings & Articles, Newspaper, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Blueprint for Medallion Exhibit, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Inaugural medals, 1892-2009; MS2035 Series 10; 7.5 linear feet.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains commemorative inaugural medals for each United States President from William McKinley to Barack Obama (as well as Thomas Jefferson and Abraham Lincoln) and vice presidents Nelson Rockerfeller and John Nance Garner. The medals range in date from 1892-2009.
  - Inaugural Medals, Thomas Jefferson, undated (Box 9, Item 1)
    General
    Bronze, 76mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Abraham Lincoln, undated (Box 9, Item 2)
  - Inaugural Medals, William McKinley, 1901 (Box 5, Item 1)
    Silver, 44 mm.
  - Inaugural Medals, William McKinley, 1901 (Box 5, Item 2)
    Bronze, 44mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Theodore Roosevelt, 1905 (Box 9, Item 3)
    Bronze, Davidson's Sons, 44mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Theodore Roosevelt, 1905 (Box 9, Item 4)
    Bronze obverse uniface cliche, Tiffany, 74mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Theodore Roosevelt, 1905 (Box 5, Item 3)
    Bronze, Tiffany. 74mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Theodore Roosevelt, 1905 (Box 5, Item 4)
    Bronze, Joseph K. Davidson's Sons, 44mm
  - Inaugural Medals, William H. Taft, 1909 (Box 9, Item 5)
    Bronze, 51mm
  - Inaugural Medals, William H. Taft, 1909 (Box 9, Item 6)
    Silver, 51mm
  - Inaugural Medals, William H. Taft, 1909 (Box 5, Item 5)
  - Inaugural Medals, Woodrow Wilson, 1913 (Box 9, Item 7)
    Bronze, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Woodrow Wilson, 1913 (Box 5, Item 6)
    Silver, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Woodrow Wilson, 1913 (Box 5, Item 7)
    Broze, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Woodrow Wilson, 1917 (Box 5, Item 9)
  - Inaugural Medals, Woodrow Wilson, 1917 (Box 5, Item 8)
    Gold, 51mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Woodrow Wilson, 1917 (Box 5, Item 10)
  - Inaugural Medals, Warren G. Harding, 1921 (Box 5, Item 11)
    Gold, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Warren G. Harding, 1921 (Box 5, Item 12)
  - Inaugural Medals, Warren G. Harding, 1921 (Box 5, Item 13)
  - Inaugural Medals, Calvin Coolidge, 1925 (Box 9, Item 8)
  - Inaugural Medals, Calvin Coolidge, 1925 (Box 5, Item 14)
  - Inaugural Medals, Herbert Hoover, 1929 (Box 5, Item 15)
  - Inaugural Medals, Herbert Hoover, 1929 (Box 9, Item 9)
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1933 (Box 9, Item 10)
    Silver, 76mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1933 (Box 9, Item 11)
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1933 (Box 9, Item 12)
    Bronze, Medallic Art, 76mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1937 (Box 9, Item 13)
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1941 (Box 9, Item 14)
    Bronze (Type 2), 42mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1937
    This item is currently missing.
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1941 (Box 5, Item 16)
    Bronze (Type 1), 42mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1941 (Box 5, Item 17)
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1945 (Box 9, Item 15)
    Bronze, 45mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Franklin Roosevelt, 1945 (Box 5, Item 18)
  - Inaugural Medals, John Nance Garner, 1932 (Box 5, Item 19)
  - Inaugural Medals, Harry Truman, 1949 (Box 9, Item 16)
  - Inaugural Medals, Harry Truman, 1949 (Box 5, Item 20)
  - Inaugural Medals, Harry Truman, 1949 (Box 5, Item 21)
  - Inaugural Medals, Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1953; Series 9 (Box 5, Item 22)
  - Inaugural Medals, Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1953 (Box 5, Item 23)
  - Inaugural Medals, Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1953 (Box 5, Item 24)
  - Inaugural Medals, Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1957 (Box 6, Item 1)
  - Inaugural Medals, Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1957 (Box 6, Item 2)
  - Inaugural Medals, Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1957 (Box 6, Item 3)
  - Inaugural Medals, John F. Kennedy, 1961 (Box 6, Item 4)
  - Inaugural Medals, John F. Kennedy, 1961 (Box 9, Item 17)
  - Inaugural Medals, Lyndon Johnson, 1965 (Box 6, Item 5)
    Gold, 27mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Lyndon Johnson, 1965 (Box 9, Item 18)
    Silver, 64mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Lyndon Johnson, 1965 (Box 10, Item 1)
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1969 (Box 6, Item 6)
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1969 (Box 6, Item 7)
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1969 (Box 6, Item 8)
    Gold, 29mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1969 (Box 10, Item 2)
    Gold-Plated Bronze in Lucite, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1969 (Box 10, Item 3)
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1973 (Box 10, Item 4)
    Antique Bronze, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1973 (Box 10, Item 5)
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1973 (Box 10, Item 6)
    Bronze, 36mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1973 (Box 6, Item 9)
    Proof Silver, 63mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1973 (Box 6, Item 10)
    Antique Silver, 63mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Richard Nixon, 1973 (Box 6, Item 11)
    Proof Bronze, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford (Vice President), 1973 (Box 6, Item 12)
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford (Vice President), 1973 (Box 6, Item 13)
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford (Vice President), 1973 (Box 6, Item 14)
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford (Vice President), 1973 (Box 10, Item 7)
    Vermeil, 63mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford, 1974 (Box 6, Item 15)
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford, 1974 (Box 6, Item 16)
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford, 1974 (Box 6, Item 17)
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford, 1974 (Box 10, Item 8)
    Gold, 32mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford, 1974 (Box 10, Item 9)
    Silver, 63mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Gerald Ford, 1974 (Box 10, Item 10)
  - Inaugural Medals, Nelson Rockerfeller, 1974 (Box 6, Item 11)
    Gold, 31mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Nelson Rockerfeller, 1974 (Box 10, Item 11)
  - Inaugural Medals, Nelson Rockerfeller, 1974 (Box 10, Item 12)
  - Inaugural Medals, Nelson Rockerfeller, 1974 (Box 10, Item 13)
  - Inaugural Medals, Nelson Rockerfeller, 1974 (Box 11, Item 1)
  - Inaugural Medals, Jimmy Carter, 1977 (Box 6, Item 18)
  - Inaugural Medals, Jimmy Carter, 1977 (Box 6, Item 19)
  - Inaugural Medals, Jimmy Carter, 1977 (Box 6, Item 20)
  - Inaugural Medals, Jimmy Carter, 1977 (Box 11, Item 2)
  - Inaugural Medals, Jimmy Carter, 1977 (Box 11, Item 3)
  - Inaugural Medals, Jimmy Carter, 1977 (Box 11, Item 4)
    Proof Silver, 32mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 6, Item 21)
    Proof Gold, 32mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 6, Item 22)
    Proof Silver, 36mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 11, Item 5)
    Antique Silver, 70mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 11, Item 6)
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 11, Item 7)
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 11, Item 8)
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 11, Item 9)
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 11, Item 10)
    Copper, 36mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1985 (Box 6, Item 23)
    Gold, 28mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1985 (Box 7, Item 1)
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1985 (Box 7, Item 2)
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1985 (Box 11, Item 11)
    Silver, 36mm
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1985 (Box 11, Item 12)
  - Inaugural Medals, Ronald Reagan, 1985 (Box 11, Item 13)
    Silver (hexagon), 50mm
  - Inaugural Medals, George H.W. Bush, 1989 (Box 7, Item 3)
  - Inaugural Medals, George H.W. Bush, 1989 (Box 7, Item 4)